1
00:00:00,288 --> 00:00:03,333
So if a photon (particle of light) is directed to 
a plane with two slits in it and either slit is observed,

2
00:00:03,333 --> 00:00:05,855
it will not go through both slits.

3
00:00:05,855 --> 00:00:07,121
If it's unobserved, it will.

4
00:00:07,121 --> 00:00:10,568
However, if it's observed after it's left
the plane but before it hits its target,

5
00:00:10,568 --> 00:00:12,377
it will not have gone though both slits.

6
00:00:12,377 --> 00:00:14,637
Agreed. What's your point?

7
00:00:14,637 --> 00:00:17,130
There's no point. I just think
it's a good idea for a T-shirt.

8
00:00:23,390 --> 00:00:24,426
Excuse me.

9
00:00:24,426 --> 00:00:26,214
Hang on.

10
00:00:29,178 --> 00:00:31,129
Uh, 1 across is "Aegean".
(Aegean Sea, the sea in southeast Europe between Greece and Turkey)

11
00:00:31,129 --> 00:00:35,298
8 down is "Nabokov" (author of <i>Lolita</i>)
26 across is "MCM"

12
00:00:35,298 --> 00:00:38,504
14 down is... move your finger...

13
00:00:38,504 --> 00:00:41,569
"Phylum" (one large biological group), which makes 
14 across "Port-au-Prince" (Capital of Haiti)

14
00:00:42,775 --> 00:00:46,463
see, "<i>Papa Doc</i>'s capital idea", that's "Port-au-Prince".
(an informal name for François  Duvalier,
the President of Haiti from 1957 to 1971)

15
00:00:47,548 --> 00:00:49,467
Haiti.

16
00:00:50,071 --> 00:00:51,899
- Can I help you?
- Yes.

17
00:00:53,939 --> 00:00:58,059
Um... is this the high-IQ sperm bank?

18
00:00:59,406 --> 00:01:02,239
If you have to ask, maybe
you shouldn't be here.

19
00:01:03,365 --> 00:01:04,933
I think this is the place.

20
00:01:06,078 --> 00:01:07,958
- Fill these out.
- Thank you.

21
00:01:07,958 --> 00:01:09,123
We'll be right back.

22
00:01:09,123 --> 00:01:12,440
Oh, take your time. I'll just
finish my crossword puzzle.

23
00:01:13,564 --> 00:01:16,077
Oh,wait.

24
00:01:26,146 --> 00:01:27,834
Leonard, I don't think I can do this.

25
00:01:28,216 --> 00:01:30,256
What are you kidding?
You're a semi-pro.

26
00:01:31,744 --> 00:01:34,275
No. We are committing genetic fraud.

27
00:01:34,275 --> 00:01:38,607
There's no guarantee that our sperm is going
to generate high-IQ offspring. Think about that.

28
00:01:38,607 --> 00:01:42,295
I have a sister with the same basic
DNA mix who hostesses at Fuddruckers.

29
00:01:43,511 --> 00:01:45,601
Sheldon, this was your idea.

30
00:01:45,601 --> 00:01:48,877
A little extra money to get fractional
T1 bandwidth (1.54Mbps) in the apartment.

31
00:01:48,877 --> 00:01:52,012
I know, and I do yearn for faster downloads.

32
00:01:52,866 --> 00:01:56,152
But there's some poor woman who's
gonna pin her hopes on my sperm.

33
00:01:56,152 --> 00:01:59,789
What if she winds up with a toddler who doesn't know
if he should use an integral or a differential

34
00:01:59,789 --> 00:02:02,342
to solve the area under a curve?

35
00:02:03,236 --> 00:02:04,915
I'm sure she'll still love him.

36
00:02:04,915 --> 00:02:06,513
I wouldn't.

37
00:02:07,990 --> 00:02:09,608
Well, what do you want to do?

38
00:02:09,608 --> 00:02:11,758
- I want to leave.
- Okay.

39
00:02:12,502 --> 00:02:14,150
What's the protocol for leaving?

40
00:02:14,150 --> 00:02:17,385
I don't know - I've never reneged
on a proffer of sperm before.

41
00:02:18,822 --> 00:02:20,772
Let's try just walking out.

42
00:02:21,254 --> 00:02:22,983
Okay.

43
00:02:32,670 --> 00:02:34,971
- Bye.
- Bye. - Nice meeting you.

44
00:02:37,885 --> 00:02:39,503
Are you still made about the sperm bank?

45
00:02:39,503 --> 00:02:41,051
No.

46
00:02:42,096 --> 00:02:44,568
You want to hear an
interesting thing about stairs?

47
00:02:45,432 --> 00:02:47,060
Not really.

48
00:02:47,060 --> 00:02:51,120
If the height of a single step is off by
2 millimetres, most people will trip

49
00:02:51,120 --> 00:02:53,220
I don't care.

50
00:02:54,345 --> 00:02:56,345
2 millimetres? That doesn't seem right.

51
00:02:56,345 --> 00:02:58,847
No, it's true. I did a series
of experiments when I was 12.

52
00:02:58,847 --> 00:03:00,958
My father broke his clavicle.

53
00:03:01,732 --> 00:03:03,802
Is that why they sent you to boarding school?

54
00:03:03,802 --> 00:03:06,796
No. That was a result of my work with lasers.

55
00:03:12,675 --> 00:03:15,258
- New neighbor?
- Evidently.

56
00:03:15,258 --> 00:03:18,232
Significant improvement over the old neighbor.

57
00:03:18,646 --> 00:03:22,945
200-pound <i>transvestite</i> with a skin condition?
(a man who enjoys dressing like a person of the opposite sex)
Yes, she is.

58
00:03:24,673 --> 00:03:26,080
- Oh, hi.
- Hi.

59
00:03:26,080 --> 00:03:27,145
- Hi.
- Hi.

60
00:03:27,145 --> 00:03:30,913
- Hi?

61
00:03:31,587 --> 00:03:33,918
We don't mean to interrupt.
We live across the hall.

62
00:03:33,918 --> 00:03:36,099
Oh, that's nice.

63
00:03:36,099 --> 00:03:38,320
Oh, no, uh, we don't live together.

64
00:03:38,320 --> 00:03:42,259
I mean, we live together, but in separate,

65
00:03:42,259 --> 00:03:44,690
heterosexual bedrooms.

66
00:03:44,690 --> 00:03:47,837
Oh. Okay, well, guess I'm your new neighbor. Penny.

67
00:03:47,837 --> 00:03:49,134
Leonard. Sheldon.

68
00:03:49,134 --> 00:03:50,069
- Hi.
- Hi.

69
00:03:50,069 --> 00:03:52,992
- Hi.
- Hi.

70
00:03:54,220 --> 00:03:57,866
Well, uh... oh, uh, welcome to the building.

71
00:03:57,866 --> 00:04:00,218
Oh,thank you. Maybe we can have coffee sometime.

72
00:04:00,218 --> 00:04:01,144
- Oh, great.
- Great.

73
00:04:01,144 --> 00:04:02,064
- Great.
- Great.

74
00:04:04,393 --> 00:04:06,171
- Well, uh, bye.
- Bye.

75
00:04:07,171 --> 00:04:09,412
- Bye.
- Bye.

76
00:04:11,353 --> 00:04:13,001
Should we have invited her for lunch?

77
00:04:13,001 --> 00:04:15,945
No. We're gonna start Season 2 of <i>Battlestar Galactica</i>.
(a franchise of science fiction films and television series)

78
00:04:17,390 --> 00:04:19,160
We already watched the season 2 DVDs.

79
00:04:19,160 --> 00:04:19,579
Not with commentary.

80
00:04:22,250 --> 00:04:25,938
I think we should be good neighbors and
invite her over, make her feel welcome.

81
00:04:26,751 --> 00:04:29,267
We never invited Louie/Louise over.

82
00:04:29,870 --> 00:04:31,722
Well... and that was wrong of us.

83
00:04:31,722 --> 00:04:33,539
We need to widen our circle.

84
00:04:33,953 --> 00:04:35,987
I have a very wide circle.

85
00:04:35,987 --> 00:04:38,876
I have 212 friends on "myspace".

86
00:04:41,131 --> 00:04:42,697
Yes, and you've never met one of them.

87
00:04:43,904 --> 00:04:45,222
That's the beauty of it.

88
00:04:47,876 --> 00:04:49,276
I'm gonna invite her over.

89
00:04:49,366 --> 00:04:52,209
We'll have a nice meal and... chat.

90
00:04:52,209 --> 00:04:55,190
Chat? We don't chat.
At least not offline.

91
00:04:57,793 --> 00:05:00,849
Well, it's not difficult.
You just listen to what she says

92
00:05:00,849 --> 00:05:03,294
and then you say something appropriate in response.

93
00:05:04,939 --> 00:05:06,271
To what end?

94
00:05:08,626 --> 00:05:09,873
Hi. Again.

95
00:05:09,873 --> 00:05:10,287
- Hi.
- Hi.

96
00:05:10,287 --> 00:05:15,790
- Hi.
- Hi!
- Anyway,um... we brought home Indian food.

97
00:05:17,108 --> 00:05:17,558
And, um...

98
00:05:18,382 --> 00:05:20,474
I know that moving can be stressful,

99
00:05:20,474 --> 00:05:22,626
and, and, I find that when I'm undergoing stress,

100
00:05:22,626 --> 00:05:25,872
that good food and company can have a comforting effect.

101
00:05:27,465 --> 00:05:30,455
Also, curry is a natural <i>laxative</i>
(a medicine or something that makes one's bowels empty easily)
and I don't have to tell you,

102
00:05:30,455 --> 00:05:35,718
that, you know, a clean colon
(the lower part of the bowels where food is changed into waste matter)
is just one less thing to worry about.

103
00:05:37,370 --> 00:05:40,000
Leonard, I'm no expert here, but I believe
in the context of a luncheon invitation,

104
00:05:40,000 --> 00:05:41,940
you might want to skip the reference to bowel movements.

105
00:05:43,355 --> 00:05:45,035
Oh, you're inviting me over to eat?

106
00:05:45,742 --> 00:05:46,821
Uh... yes.

107
00:05:46,871 --> 00:05:49,631
Oh, that's so nice. I'd love to.

108
00:05:49,681 --> 00:05:50,368
Great.

109
00:05:50,870 --> 00:05:53,020
So, what do you guys do for fun around here?

110
00:05:53,879 --> 00:05:55,806
Well, today we tried masturbating for money.

111
00:06:00,000 --> 00:06:03,307
Our whole universe was
in a hot, dense state

112
00:06:03,307 --> 00:06:07,405
then nearly 14 billion years ago
expansion started... wait!

113
00:06:07,555 --> 00:06:10,077
The earth began to cool
the <i>autotrophs</i> (microorganism) began to drool

114
00:06:10,077 --> 00:06:12,376
<i>neanderthals</i> (an early type of human being) developed tools
we built the wall

115
00:06:12,376 --> 00:06:14,908
we built the pyramids
math, science, history,

116
00:06:14,908 --> 00:06:17,167
unraveling the mystery that all started

117
00:06:17,167 --> 00:06:18,570
with a big bang bang!

118
00:06:20,418 --> 00:06:22,429
<font color="#ffff00">Subtitle presented by rhapsody</font>

119
00:06:22,429 --> 00:06:24,107
<font color="#ffff00">Synchro: rhapsody</font>

120
00:06:24,107 --> 00:06:25,464
<font color="#ffff00">THE BIG BANG THEORY
Season 01  Episode 01</font>

121
00:06:25,554 --> 00:06:27,303
Okay, well, make yourself at home.

122
00:06:27,303 --> 00:06:28,981
Okay. Thank you.

123
00:06:28,981 --> 00:06:30,769
You're very welcome.

124
00:06:34,498 --> 00:06:37,411
This looks like some serious stuff.
Leonard, did you do this?

125
00:06:37,411 --> 00:06:39,592
Actually, that's my work.

126
00:06:40,446 --> 00:06:41,381
Wow.

127
00:06:41,381 --> 00:06:46,274
Yeah. Well, it's just some <i>quantum mechanics</i> (study of the way
particles behave), with a little <i>string theory</i> doodling around the edges.
(a unifying physics theory to explain the nature of all known forces & matter)

128
00:06:46,274 --> 00:06:47,923
That part there, that's just a joke.

129
00:06:47,923 --> 00:06:51,528
It's a spoof of the Born-Oppenheimer approximation 
(the assumption that the electronic motion and
the nuclear motion in molecules can be separated)

130
00:06:52,375 --> 00:06:55,941
So you're like one of those
<i>beautiful mind</i> genius guys.

131
00:06:56,887 --> 00:06:58,334
Yeah.

132
00:06:59,469 --> 00:07:00,896
This is really impressive.

133
00:07:00,896 --> 00:07:03,479
I have a board. If you like boards, this is my board.

134
00:07:04,945 --> 00:07:06,332
Holy smokes!

135
00:07:06,332 --> 00:07:09,960
If by "holy smokes" you mean a derivative restatement of the kind of stuff

136
00:07:09,960 --> 00:07:13,377
you can find scribbled on the wall of any men's room at MIT, sure.

137
00:07:13,929 --> 00:07:15,266
- What?
- Come on.

138
00:07:15,266 --> 00:07:18,643
Who hasn't seen this differential below "here I sit, broken-hearted"?

139
00:07:19,386 --> 00:07:23,396
At least I didn't have to invent 26 dimensions
(Real space has only 3 dimensions: length, width, depth)
just to make the math come out.

140
00:07:23,396 --> 00:07:25,074
I didn't invent them. They're there.

141
00:07:25,074 --> 00:07:26,079
In what universe?

142
00:07:26,079 --> 00:07:28,359
In all of them - that is the point.

143
00:07:28,822 --> 00:07:30,671
Uh... do you guys mind if I start?

144
00:07:30,671 --> 00:07:32,992
Um... Penny...

145
00:07:32,992 --> 00:07:35,224
that's where I sit.

146
00:07:36,489 --> 00:07:38,398
So, sit next to me.

147
00:07:39,383 --> 00:07:41,705
No... I sit there.

148
00:07:42,518 --> 00:07:44,398
- What's the difference?
- What's the difference?!

149
00:07:44,398 --> 00:07:46,136
Here we go.

150
00:07:46,599 --> 00:07:49,593
In the winter, that seat is close enough to the radiator to remain warm,

151
00:07:49,593 --> 00:07:52,648
and yet not so close as to cause perspiration; in the summer,

152
00:07:52,648 --> 00:07:56,497
it's directly in the path of a cross-breeze
created by opening windows there, and there.

153
00:07:56,497 --> 00:07:59,351
It faces the television at an angle that is neither direct,

154
00:07:59,351 --> 00:08:00,878
thus discouraging conversation,

155
00:08:00,878 --> 00:08:03,340
nor so far wide as to create a <i>parallax</i> distortion.
(an optical effect that contributes to the perception of relative distances)

156
00:08:03,340 --> 00:08:07,199
I could go on, but I think I've made my point.

157
00:08:09,872 --> 00:08:11,309
Do you want me to move?

158
00:08:11,309 --> 00:08:13,821
- Well...
- Just sit somewhere else.

159
00:08:15,609 --> 00:08:16,870
Fine.

160
00:08:34,423 --> 00:08:36,366
Sheldon, sit!

161
00:08:38,190 --> 00:08:38,776
Ah.

162
00:08:41,677 --> 00:08:43,163
Well, this is nice.

163
00:08:43,163 --> 00:08:44,872
We don't have a lot of company over.

164
00:08:44,872 --> 00:08:47,655
That's not true - Koothrappali and Wolowitz come over all the time.

165
00:08:47,655 --> 00:08:48,721
Yes, I know, but...

166
00:08:48,721 --> 00:08:51,012
Tuesday night we played Klingon Boggle till 1:00 in the morning.

167
00:08:51,012 --> 00:08:52,208
Yeah, I remember.

168
00:08:52,208 --> 00:08:53,705
I resent you saying we don't have company.

169
00:08:53,705 --> 00:08:55,043
- I'm sorry.
- That has negative social implications.

170
00:08:55,043 --> 00:08:57,092
I said I'm sorry!

171
00:08:58,337 --> 00:09:01,171
So... Klingon Boggle?

172
00:09:01,171 --> 00:09:05,071
Yeah. It's like regular boggle, 
but... in Klingon (an alien language in "Star Trek").

173
00:09:08,256 --> 00:09:11,210
That's probably enough about us.
So, tell us about you.

174
00:09:11,210 --> 00:09:13,773
Um... me? Okay.

175
00:09:13,773 --> 00:09:17,662
I'm a Sagittarius, which probably tells you
way more than you need to know.

176
00:09:17,662 --> 00:09:21,179
Yes. It tells us that you participate in the mass cultural delusion

177
00:09:21,179 --> 00:09:25,299
that the sun's apparent position relative to arbitrarily
defined constellations at the time of your birth

178
00:09:25,299 --> 00:09:28,183
somehow affects your personality.

179
00:09:30,132 --> 00:09:31,962
Participate in the what?

180
00:09:31,962 --> 00:09:36,876
I think what sheldon's trying to say is that
Sagittarius wouldn't have been our first guess.

181
00:09:36,876 --> 00:09:39,749
Oh, yeah. A lot of people think I'm a <i>water sign</i>.
(Cancer, Scorpio, or Pisces)

182
00:09:40,353 --> 00:09:42,231
Okay, let's see, what else.

183
00:09:42,231 --> 00:09:44,362
Oh, I'm a vegetarian. Except for fish.

184
00:09:44,362 --> 00:09:46,874
And the occasional steak. I love steak!

185
00:09:48,316 --> 00:09:52,572
Well, that's interesting. Leonard can't process corn.

186
00:09:56,621 --> 00:09:58,250
Well, uh, do you have some sort of a job?

187
00:09:58,250 --> 00:10:00,649
Oh, yeah. I'm a waitress at the <i>Cheesecake Factory</i> (a chain restaurant).

188
00:10:01,867 --> 00:10:03,337
Oh... I love cheesecake.

189
00:10:03,337 --> 00:10:04,350
You're <i>lactose</i> intolerant.
(a type of sugar found in milk)

190
00:10:04,350 --> 00:10:06,350
I don't eat it - I just think it's a good idea.

191
00:10:08,000 --> 00:10:10,036
Oh. Anyways, I'm also writing a screenplay.

192
00:10:10,136 --> 00:10:13,569
It's about this sensitive girl who comes to L.A. from Lincoln, Nebraska,

193
00:10:13,569 --> 00:10:16,921
to be an actress and winds up a waitress at the Cheesecake Factory.

194
00:10:18,754 --> 00:10:20,426
So, it's based on your life.

195
00:10:20,622 --> 00:10:21,709
No, I'm from Omaha.

196
00:10:26,268 --> 00:10:27,871
Well, if that was movie, I would go see it.

197
00:10:27,871 --> 00:10:29,073
I know, right?

198
00:10:30,145 --> 00:10:32,459
Okay, let's see, what else... um...

199
00:10:32,559 --> 00:10:34,436
Guess that's about it.

200
00:10:35,083 --> 00:10:36,315
That's the story of Penny.

201
00:10:37,270 --> 00:10:39,421
Well, it sounds wonderful.

202
00:10:39,571 --> 00:10:41,493
It was.

203
00:10:41,693 --> 00:10:44,584
Until I fell in love with a jerk!

204
00:10:50,253 --> 00:10:51,950
<i>- What's happening?
- I don't know.</i>

205
00:10:52,486 --> 00:10:54,883
God, you know, four years I lived with him.

206
00:10:54,883 --> 00:10:57,749
Four years - that's like as long as high school!

207
00:10:57,849 --> 00:10:59,959
It took you four years to get through high school?

208
00:11:02,390 --> 00:11:05,518
It just... I can't believe I trusted him!

209
00:11:10,442 --> 00:11:13,266
Should I say something?
I feel like I should say something.

210
00:11:13,266 --> 00:11:14,829
You? No, you'll only make it worse.

211
00:11:15,029 --> 00:11:16,606
You want to know the most pathetic part?

212
00:11:17,222 --> 00:11:20,047
Even though I hate his lying, cheating guts...

213
00:11:20,977 --> 00:11:22,753
I still love him.

214
00:11:22,953 --> 00:11:24,594
Is that crazy?

215
00:11:24,694 --> 00:11:25,403
Yes.

216
00:11:28,271 --> 00:11:29,850
No, it's not crazy.

217
00:11:29,850 --> 00:11:32,759
It's uh... uh... it's a paradox.

218
00:11:32,959 --> 00:11:35,614
The paradoxes are part of nature.

219
00:11:35,714 --> 00:11:39,262
Think about light. If you look at Huygens, light is a wave,

220
00:11:39,262 --> 00:11:41,290
as confirmed by the double-slit experiment,

221
00:11:41,390 --> 00:11:47,292
but then along comes Albert Einstein and
discovers that light behaves like particles, too.

222
00:11:49,469 --> 00:11:51,366
Well, I didn't make it worse.

223
00:11:53,443 --> 00:11:55,706
I'm so sorry. I'm such a mess.

224
00:11:55,906 --> 00:12:00,254
On top of everything else, I'm all gross from
moving and my stupid shower doesn't even work.

225
00:12:00,354 --> 00:12:01,569
Our shower works.

226
00:12:03,033 --> 00:12:04,977
Really? Would it be totally weird if I used it?

227
00:12:05,177 --> 00:12:05,880
Yes.

228
00:12:06,089 --> 00:12:06,690
- No.
- No?

229
00:12:06,890 --> 00:12:08,112
- No.
- No.

230
00:12:09,273 --> 00:12:10,514
It's right down the hall.

231
00:12:11,028 --> 00:12:13,754
Thanks. You guys are really sweet.

232
00:12:20,134 --> 00:12:22,518
Well, this is an interesting development.

233
00:12:25,862 --> 00:12:27,104
How so?

234
00:12:27,204 --> 00:12:30,757
It has been some time since we've had a
woman take her clothes off in our apartment.

235
00:12:31,652 --> 00:12:35,831
That's not true. Remember at thanksgiving my grandmother
with  <i>Alzheimer's</i> had that episode?
(a disease that affects the brain, especially of old people)

236
00:12:38,150 --> 00:12:41,659
Point taken. It has been some time since
we've had a woman take her clothes off,

237
00:12:41,659 --> 00:12:43,615
after which we didn't want to rip our eyes out.

238
00:12:45,547 --> 00:12:48,217
The worst part was watching her carve that turkey.

239
00:12:49,688 --> 00:12:52,564
So what exactly are you trying to accomplish here?

240
00:12:53,547 --> 00:12:54,390
Excuse me?

241
00:12:54,696 --> 00:12:56,934
That woman in there is not going to have sex with you.

242
00:12:57,060 --> 00:12:59,395
Well, I'm not trying to have sex with her.

243
00:12:59,604 --> 00:13:01,820
Oh, good. Then you won't be disappointed.

244
00:13:02,593 --> 00:13:05,234
What makes you think she wouldn't have sex with me?

245
00:13:05,234 --> 00:13:06,982
I'm a male and she's a female.

246
00:13:07,799 --> 00:13:10,144
Yes, but not of the same species.

247
00:13:11,045 --> 00:13:13,350
I'm not going to engage in hypotheticals here.

248
00:13:13,350 --> 00:13:14,877
I'm just trying to be a good neighbor.

249
00:13:15,077 --> 00:13:16,592
Oh, of course.

250
00:13:16,792 --> 00:13:21,883
That's not to say that if a carnal relationship
were to develop that I wouldn't participate.

251
00:13:23,975 --> 00:13:25,552
However briefly.

252
00:13:26,920 --> 00:13:29,205
Do you think this possibility will be helped or hindered

253
00:13:29,205 --> 00:13:32,268
when she discovers your <i>Luke Skywalker</i>
("Star Wars") no-more-tears shampoo?

254
00:13:34,082 --> 00:13:35,359
It's <i>Darth Vader</i> ("Star Wars") shampoo.

255
00:13:37,436 --> 00:13:39,228
Luke Skywalker's the conditioner.

256
00:13:42,191 --> 00:13:43,318
Wait till you see this.

257
00:13:43,418 --> 00:13:44,539
It's fantastic, unbelievable.

258
00:13:44,639 --> 00:13:46,107
See what?

259
00:13:47,098 --> 00:13:51,101
It's a Stephen Hawking
(a leading theoretical physicist in the field of theoretical cosmology)
lecture from MIT in 1974.

260
00:13:51,201 --> 00:13:54,039
This isn't a good time.

261
00:13:54,539 --> 00:13:55,579
It's before he became a creepy computer voice.

262
00:13:58,834 --> 00:14:00,163
That's great. You guys have to go.

263
00:14:00,263 --> 00:14:00,761
Why?

264
00:14:00,861 --> 00:14:01,965
It's just not a good time.

265
00:14:02,065 --> 00:14:03,742
Leonard has a lady over.

266
00:14:04,524 --> 00:14:06,399
Yeah, right - your grandmother back in town?

267
00:14:09,322 --> 00:14:11,239
No. And she's not a lady.

268
00:14:11,239 --> 00:14:12,297
She's just a new neighbor.

269
00:14:13,000 --> 00:14:15,667
Hang on, there really is a lady here?

270
00:14:15,799 --> 00:14:16,559
Uh-huh.

271
00:14:16,800 --> 00:14:18,659
And you want us out because you're anticipating coitus?

272
00:14:20,029 --> 00:14:21,806
I'm not anticipating coitus.

273
00:14:21,906 --> 00:14:23,000
So she's available for coitus?

274
00:14:23,300 --> 00:14:25,494
Can we please just stop saying "coitus"?

275
00:14:25,594 --> 00:14:27,500
Technically, that would be "coitus interruptus".

276
00:14:29,263 --> 00:14:32,197
Hey, is there a trick to getting
it to switch from tub to shower...?

277
00:14:32,663 --> 00:14:35,018
Oh, hi. Sorry. Hello~

278
00:14:37,111 --> 00:14:38,907
Enchanté! Mademoiselle.
(French: Pleased to meet you! Miss.)

279
00:14:41,010 --> 00:14:43,825
Howard Wolowitz,
Cal Tech (California Institute of Technology),
Department of Applied Physics.

280
00:14:43,925 --> 00:14:45,872
You may be familiar with some of my work.

281
00:14:45,972 --> 00:14:50,944
It's currently orbiting Jupiter's largest moon
taking high-resolution digital photographs.

282
00:14:52,641 --> 00:14:54,373
Penny. I work at the cheesecake factory.

283
00:14:55,472 --> 00:14:57,004
Come on, I'll show you the trick with the shower.

284
00:14:57,912 --> 00:14:58,917
Bonne douche.

285
00:14:59,217 --> 00:15:01,000
I'm... I'm sorry?

286
00:15:01,249 --> 00:15:03,000
It's French for "good shower".

287
00:15:03,100 --> 00:15:05,000
It's a sentiment I can express in six languages.

288
00:15:06,755 --> 00:15:08,186
Save it for your blog, Howard.

289
00:15:10,058 --> 00:15:11,387
洗个痛快澡!
(Mandarin: Good shower!)

290
00:15:16,490 --> 00:15:18,661
All right, there it goes.
It sticks. I'm sorry.

291
00:15:18,811 --> 00:15:19,032
Okay, thanks.

292
00:15:20,032 --> 00:15:21,885
You' welcome. Oh, you're just going to step right...
Okay, I'll...

293
00:15:23,589 --> 00:15:25,792
- Hey, Leonard...
- The hair products are Sheldon's.

294
00:15:26,154 --> 00:15:27,479
Okay.

295
00:15:27,751 --> 00:15:29,862
Um, can I ask you a favor?

296
00:15:30,200 --> 00:15:31,210
A favor?

297
00:15:31,848 --> 00:15:34,000
Sure, you can ask me a favor.
I would do you a favor for you.

298
00:15:35,986 --> 00:15:37,230
It's okay if you say no.

299
00:15:37,330 --> 00:15:39,000
Oh, I'll probably say yes.

300
00:15:40,155 --> 00:15:43,000
It's just not the kind of thing
you ask a guy you just met.

301
00:15:44,644 --> 00:15:45,604
Wow.

302
00:15:54,319 --> 00:15:57,124
I really think we should examine
the chain of causality here.

303
00:15:57,224 --> 00:15:57,900
Must we?

304
00:15:58,100 --> 00:16:00,682
Event A: a beautiful woman
stands naked in our shower.

305
00:16:00,782 --> 00:16:03,709
Event B: we drive halfway across
town to retrieve a television set.

306
00:16:03,709 --> 00:16:06,067
from the aforementioned woman's ex-boyfriend.

307
00:16:06,167 --> 00:16:12,287
Query: on what plane of existence is there
even a semi-rational link between these events?

308
00:16:13,464 --> 00:16:15,409
She asked me to do her a favor, Sheldon.

309
00:16:15,509 --> 00:16:18,494
Ah, yes. Well, that may be the <i>proximal</i> (nearest)
cause of our journey,

310
00:16:18,494 --> 00:16:22,393
but we both know it only exists 
in contradistinction to the higher level distal cause.
(in contrast with the underlying cause)

311
00:16:22,393 --> 00:16:22,813
Which is?

312
00:16:23,013 --> 00:16:25,062
You think with your penis.

313
00:16:26,676 --> 00:16:28,138
That's a biological impossibility.

314
00:16:28,238 --> 00:16:29,622
And you didn't have to come.

315
00:16:30,078 --> 00:16:34,710
Oh, right, yes, I could have stayed behind and watch 
Wolowitz try to hit on Penny in Russian, Arabic and Farsi.

316
00:16:35,511 --> 00:16:36,910
Why can't she get her own TV?

317
00:16:36,910 --> 00:16:39,370
Come on, you know how it is with break-ups.

318
00:16:39,470 --> 00:16:41,738
No, I don't... and neither do you.

319
00:16:41,838 --> 00:16:44,228
I... I broke up with Joyce Kim.

320
00:16:44,328 --> 00:16:47,452
You did not break up with Joyce Kim. 
She defected to North Korea.

321
00:16:47,652 --> 00:16:50,014
To mend her broken heart.

322
00:16:53,587 --> 00:16:55,734
This situation is much less complicated.

323
00:16:55,834 --> 00:17:00,000
There's some kind of dispute between Penny and
her ex-boyfriend as to who gets custody of the TV.

324
00:17:00,100 --> 00:17:02,867
She just wanted to avoid having a scene with him.

325
00:17:02,967 --> 00:17:04,782
So we get to have a scene with him?

326
00:17:04,882 --> 00:17:06,613
No, Sheldon, there's not going to be a scene.

327
00:17:06,613 --> 00:17:08,762
There's two of us and one of him.

328
00:17:09,457 --> 00:17:11,310
Leonard, the two of us can't even carry a TV.

329
00:17:14,176 --> 00:17:16,625
So, you guys work with Leonard and Sheldon at the university?

330
00:17:22,226 --> 00:17:24,643
Um, I'm sorry. Do you speak english?

331
00:17:24,643 --> 00:17:27,550
Oh, he speaks English.
He just can't speak to women.

332
00:17:29,000 --> 00:17:30,465
Really? Why?

333
00:17:30,565 --> 00:17:32,210
He's kind of a nerd.

334
00:17:35,335 --> 00:17:36,611
Juice box?
(pronounced intentionally like G-Spot...)

335
00:17:41,500 --> 00:17:42,612
I'll do the talking.

336
00:17:42,712 --> 00:17:43,600
[Man:] Yeah?

337
00:17:43,700 --> 00:17:45,708
Uh, hi, I'm Leonard, this is Sheldon.

338
00:17:45,808 --> 00:17:47,348
- Hello.
- Let's...

339
00:17:49,139 --> 00:17:51,605
Uh, we're here to pick up Penny's TV.

340
00:17:51,705 --> 00:17:52,732
[Man:] Get lost.

341
00:17:52,832 --> 00:17:53,815
Okay, thanks for you time.

342
00:17:54,338 --> 00:17:56,300
We're not going to give up just like that.

343
00:17:56,400 --> 00:17:57,893
Leonard, the TV's in the building.

344
00:17:57,893 --> 00:18:00,558
We have been denied access to the building
- ergo (therefore), we are done.

345
00:18:00,658 --> 00:18:02,179
Excuse me.

346
00:18:02,179 --> 00:18:04,684
If I were to give up on the first little hitch
I never would have been able

347
00:18:04,684 --> 00:18:08,948
to identify the fingerprints of string theory
in the aftermath of the big bang.

348
00:18:10,000 --> 00:18:12,336
My apologies. What's your plan?

349
00:18:26,012 --> 00:18:29,097
It's just a privilege to watch your mind at work.

350
00:18:29,851 --> 00:18:32,785
Come on, we have a combined IQ of 360.

351
00:18:32,785 --> 00:18:35,839
We should be able to figure out how to get into a stupid building.

352
00:18:39,739 --> 00:18:41,287
What do you think their combined IQ is?

353
00:18:41,387 --> 00:18:43,106
Just grab the door!

354
00:18:45,465 --> 00:18:46,683
This is it.

355
00:18:47,907 --> 00:18:49,254
I'll do the talking.

356
00:18:49,354 --> 00:18:51,346
Good thinking. I'll just be the muscle.

357
00:18:59,012 --> 00:19:00,008
Yeah?

358
00:19:00,108 --> 00:19:02,269
I'm Leonard, this is Sheldon.

359
00:19:02,269 --> 00:19:03,531
From the <i>Intercom</i>. (an Internet service provider)

360
00:19:05,343 --> 00:19:07,232
How the hell did you get in the building?

361
00:19:07,332 --> 00:19:10,850
Uh... we're scientists.

362
00:19:12,387 --> 00:19:14,489
Tell him about our IQ.

363
00:19:26,868 --> 00:19:28,727
- Leonard...
- What?

364
00:19:28,727 --> 00:19:29,834
My mom bought me those pants.

365
00:19:29,934 --> 00:19:30,474
I'm sorry.

366
00:19:32,174 --> 00:19:33,743
You're going to have to call her.

367
00:19:36,897 --> 00:19:39,922
Sheldon, I am so sorry I dragged you through this.

368
00:19:40,022 --> 00:19:43,622
It's okay. It wasn't my first pantsing and it won't be my last.

369
00:19:44,645 --> 00:19:46,242
And you were right about my motives.

370
00:19:46,242 --> 00:19:51,771
I was hoping to establish a relationship
with Penny that might have someday led to sex.

371
00:19:53,016 --> 00:19:54,995
Well, you got me out of my pants.

372
00:19:57,096 --> 00:19:58,654
Anyway, I've learned my lesson.

373
00:19:58,754 --> 00:20:00,613
She's out of my league.
I'm done with her.

374
00:20:00,713 --> 00:20:05,145
Got my work,
one day I'll win the Nobel Prize and then I'll die alone.

375
00:20:05,245 --> 00:20:08,010
Don't think like that.
You're not going to die alone.

376
00:20:08,210 --> 00:20:10,493
Thank you, Sheldon. You're a good friend.

377
00:20:12,391 --> 00:20:14,373
And you're certainly not going to win a Nobel Prize.

378
00:20:15,800 --> 00:20:19,476
This is one of my favorite places to kick back after a quest.

379
00:20:19,776 --> 00:20:21,097
They have a great house <i>ale</i> (beer).

380
00:20:21,897 --> 00:20:22,843
Wow, a cool tiger.

381
00:20:23,043 --> 00:20:24,985
Yeah, I've had him since Level 10.

382
00:20:26,059 --> 00:20:27,859
His name is buttons.

383
00:20:28,559 --> 00:20:33,033
Anyway, if you had your own game character
we could hang out, maybe go on a quest.

384
00:20:34,157 --> 00:20:36,088
Um... sounds interesting.

385
00:20:36,488 --> 00:20:37,300
So you'll think about it?

386
00:20:37,400 --> 00:20:39,758
Oh, I don't think I'll be able to stop thinking about it.

387
00:20:42,106 --> 00:20:43,275
Smooth.

388
00:20:45,824 --> 00:20:46,568
We're home.

389
00:20:46,668 --> 00:20:48,899
Oh, my god, what happened?

390
00:20:48,999 --> 00:20:53,787
Well, your ex-boyfriend sends his regards and
I think the rest is fairly self-explanatory.

391
00:20:54,687 --> 00:20:56,395
I'm so sorry.

392
00:20:56,495 --> 00:20:59,291
I really thought if you guys went
instead of me he wouldn't be such an ass.

393
00:20:59,391 --> 00:21:01,551
No, it was a valid hypothesis.

394
00:21:01,651 --> 00:21:04,000
That was a valid hypoth...
What is happening to you?

395
00:21:05,500 --> 00:21:08,600
Really... thank you so much for going and trying.

396
00:21:08,700 --> 00:21:11,249
Oh, you're so terrific.

397
00:21:11,724 --> 00:21:12,300
Really.

398
00:21:13,851 --> 00:21:17,469
Why don't you get some clothes on? 
I'll get my purse, and dinner is on me, okay?

399
00:21:17,669 --> 00:21:18,698
- Really? Great.
- Thank you.
- Okay.

400
00:21:25,447 --> 00:21:26,758
You're not done with her, are you?

401
00:21:28,694 --> 00:21:30,848
Our babies will be smart and beautiful.

402
00:21:33,700 --> 00:21:35,451
Not to mention imaginary.

403
00:21:43,500 --> 00:21:46,250
- Is Thai food okay with you, Penny?
- Sure.

404
00:21:46,350 --> 00:21:48,565
We can't have Thai food
- we had Indian for lunch.

405
00:21:48,665 --> 00:21:49,166
So?

406
00:21:49,266 --> 00:21:51,186
They're both curry-based cuisines.

407
00:21:51,286 --> 00:21:51,660
So?

408
00:21:51,760 --> 00:21:54,038
It would be <i>gastronomically redundant</i>.
(on the art of cooking food, both are basically the same thing)

409
00:21:54,138 --> 00:21:56,541
I can see we're going to have to spell out everything for this girl.

410
00:21:58,389 --> 00:21:59,655
Any ideas, Raj?

411
00:22:02,171 --> 00:22:04,366
Uh, turn left on lake street and head up to Colorado.

412
00:22:04,466 --> 00:22:07,249
I know a wonderful little sushi bar that has karaoke.

413
00:22:07,349 --> 00:22:08,328
That sounds like fun.

414
00:22:09,729 --> 00:22:15,480
<i>Baby, baby, don't get hooked on me...</i>

415
00:22:15,580 --> 00:22:20,300
<i>oh, baby, baby, don't get hooked on me...</i>

416
00:22:22,000 --> 00:22:24,089
I don't know what your odds are in the world as a whole,

417
00:22:24,189 --> 00:22:26,146
but as far as the population of this cargoes,

418
00:22:26,196 --> 00:22:27,741
you're a veritable <i>mack daddy</i>. 
(one who is good with the opposite sex)

419
00:22:33,200 --> 00:22:34,700
<font color="#ffff00">Thanks for watching the episode in this subtitle
Goodbye!</font>

