So,to make a long story short,
they say it's my fault for leaving
the pistolon the seat of the Jeep.
I say it's the general's
fault for sitting on it.
But either way,I'm not allowed
to have a gun for a while.
And a weary nation
breathes a sigh of relief.
Yeah,yeah,terrific.
Um,so,they've got you
working in the kitchen?
Yeah,we call it the mess.
That corn's not gonna
cream itself,Harper!
Yes,sir. Sorry,sir.
Uh,I got to go back to workdefending our
nation against terrorists and what not.
Take care of yourself,buddy.
Don't worry,Dad.I'm being all I can be.
Seems like just yesterday
he was an adorable,
chubby-cheeked little boy catching a
Frisbeeon the beach in Santa Monica.
Now he's a fuzz-faced buck privatecatching
the clap from a whore in Tijuana.
Hey,guys.What do you think?
Oh,yummy.
You look like the maitre d' in heaven.
What's the occasion?
It's Zoey's birthday.
Oh,well,tell her happy
birthday.What are you gonna give her?
The rest of my life.
Beg your pardon?
I'm gonna ask her to marry me.
Hello. Are you serious?
Absolutely.
Wow,wow,that's,uh...
What he's trying to say
is,once you're married,
where's he gonna live?
No,no,stop,please.No,what
I'm trying to say is,
I think it's wonderful,and
I'm very happy for you.
I figured,why not,you know?I
mean,I love her,I love her daughter.
Yeah,it's win-win for everybody.
Gonna miss you.
Hey,I don't want to get ahead of myself,
but I was hoping you'd be my best man.
Oh,uh,Walden,I'd be honored to
be the best man at your wedding.
What's so funny?
You wouldn't be the best man
at the Dinah Shore Golf Classic.
All right,you can be the maid of honor.
Okay,I got to go.
Good luck with Zoey.
Oh,thanks,but I mean,come on.
How about that?The
kid's getting married.
Yeah. Crazy,huh?
If I looked like him,I wouldn't
take myself off the market.
Is that so?
Oh,yeah,I'd be out there every
nightwearing my penis down to a nub.
It would look like a golf pencil.
Hey,a golf pencil does
a lot of scoring,lady.
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=-
-=http://ytet.org=-   proudly presents
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=-Sync:
YTET- ÑÅ±´
Two And a Half
Men  Season 10 Episode 1
Two and a Half Men 10x01  I
Changed My Mind About the Milk
This is magnificent.
As are you.
Happy birthday.
Thank you.
Zoey,my life is so much
better with you in it.
The first time I saw
you,it was like...fireworks.
- Did you...
- I did.
And when I hear your voice...
...it's like music.
Music.
Sorry.
Oh,God,Walden,all this for my birthday?
Not just for your birthday.
You see,Zoey,when a man loves a woman...
...he can't keep his
mind on nothin' else.
Okay,I'm totally lost now.
He'd give up all his comforts
and sleep out in the rain,
if she said that's
the way it ought to be.
Wait,that's from some song.
No,no,not some song;a great song.
Bolton,you're up.
* When a man loves a woman *
* He can't keep his
mind on nothin' else *
* He'd trade the world... *
Get up,get up.Stop it.
Zoey Hyde-Tottingham Pierce...
...will you do me the honor of
becomingZoey Hyde-Tottingham Pierce Schmidt?
No. I'm sorry.I can't do it.
Zoey!
Shut up,Bolton!
So,after they get married,
I don't know what I'm going to do.
Oh,Alan,don't be coy.
If you want to come
live with me,just ask.
Can I come live with you?
No.
Come on,Mom,I'm gonna be homeless.
Once he marries her,I'm
gonna be living on the street.
Try to pick a street in
Beverly Hillsso I can visit you.
Does this guy belong to you?
Michael Bolton?
Hi,Alan.
Uh,yes,bring him in.
What happened?
She said no.
Oh,oh,Walden,I am so sorry.
When I proposed,she just
ran out of the restaurant.
Now she won't return my
callsor e-mails or texts.
It's like she's ignoring meacross
the entire digital spectrum.
It's like she's Amish.
So...you went out drinking
and ended up picking up Michael Bolton?
No.I hired him to sing
while I was proposing.
I should've gone with Josh Groban.
Wait,you're gonna blame me for this?
I'm gonna call her again.
Oh,my stars.Michael Bolton.
I have a vibrator named after you.
Zoey,why won't you
answer?Was it something I did?
Was the ring not big
enough?Was it Bolton?
Hey!
Okay.Screw it,I just
can't sit around here.
Come on,Bolton,let's go find her.
I'm not gonna go looking
for your girlfriend.
Why don't you see if Groban's available?
Hey,I bought and paid
for your ass until 10:00.
It's 10:01.So now you can kiss it.
Fine,I'll just drive myself.
Oh,no,no,hang on,hang on.
You can't drive.I'll take you.
See,you're a good
friend.You're dead to me.
I can't believe the
things I do for money.
You won't believe the
things I'll do for free.
I really,really think you ought
to waittill tomorrow to do this.
No,no,I need to know why.
Not a good idea.
See,it's like asking a woman
why she won't sleep with you.
You always hope that
it's 'cause you're too big
and you'll ruin her for other men.
But no,it's usually 'cause she
sobered upand got a good look at you.
Oh,Walden.
That's the sound they make.
We need to talk.
Can we do this tomorrow?
Let me use a word that
you're fond of:"No."
Have you been drinking?
Let me use a word that
you're not fond of:"Yes."
She's right,Walden. You
can come back tomorrow.
No. I'm not leaving
until I get an answer.
Walden,please.
Zoey,I need an answer.
Oh,it's complicated.
No.
Peeing with morning wood is complicated.
True. That thing is like a Water Wiggle.
Once,I shorted out a light
socket in the ceiling.
- I've done that.
- Yeah.
Saying yes to someone who
loves youmore than life itself
is not complicated.
Fine. Do you really want to know?
I really want to know.
Oh,hang on,hang on. Okay,okay.
This is a textbook exampleof
what I was talking about earlier.
When a woman says,"Do
you really want to know?"
you think you want to know,but trust me,
you don't really want to know.
No,I really want to know.
There's someone else.
You're right.I did not want to know.
It's someone I was involved
with many years ago,
and he's having a
very,very rough time and...
and he needs me.
Oh.Well,that clears it up.
Hey,if you like hanging outwith
guys who are down on their luck,
why don't you just shack
up with my loser friend?
Um,I'm actually not available.
Wait a minute,there's another guy?
Yep.
Better than Walden?
Apparently.
I'm sorry,unless this new
guy can fly around the room
and shoot fire out his
ass,that bitch is crazy.
Hey.
Well,hey,look who's finally
up.How you feeling,buddy?
A little hungover.
Berta,you got any pot brownies?
Until they cure glaucoma.
Thanks.
You want a glass of milkor
something to wash that down with?
No,I'm good. Thanks.
Instead of getting loaded,maybe
you want to talk about it?
What is there to talk about,Alan?
She's with another guy!
I changed my mind about the milk.
I mean,how can another
guy give her anything
that I can't give her?
Maybe he doesn't talk
with his mouth full.
You know what?I don't think
the other guy can give her
anything I can't.
Well,you're probably right.
Probably?
Definitely!
You know what? Let's just make a list.
Okay,here we go. Look at this.
Walden... and the other
guy.Let's just call him "Dick."
Okay.Ability to
provide.Walden-- billionaire.
Dick? Less.
That's one point for me.Okay,looks.
You win.
Thank you,Berta.
I didn't want to say so myself.
Oh! Humility.That's
two more checks for me.
Okay,what else? Oh,just
an all-around great guy.
Everybody likes me.Who likes Dick?
- Um...
- Berta,please.
Oh,God.Zoey likes Dick.
Who am I kidding?Zoey loves Dick!
Oh,hey,hey.Take it easy.
I miss her,Alan.I miss
the way she looks at me.
Yeah.
Her smile.
Sure,sure.
Her hair.
Her cute little butt.
Hello,sailor.
Just the way our bodies
just fit perfectly together.
Damn,I should've hugged him.
Trust me,buddy,a stranger in your bed
is not gonna chase
away the memory of Zoey.
What do you suggest I do?
Well,what usually helps me is
a bottle of supermarket vodka
and masturbating using
my tears as lubricant.
So I'm just supposed to
accept being alone forever?
Hey,you will never be alonebecause
I will never leave you.
- Thanks.
- Can't get rid of me.
I'm like a dry cough.
Yeah,you might be onto something.
Maybe I should just give up women.
We should go gay!
Good one.
But no,I'm serious.
Really?
Okay,okay,if we're gonna
do it,we got to do it right.
We'll get married in New
Hampshire,uh,register at Pottery Barn,
adopt a Chinese baby.
Ooh,we can wear scarves at our wedding!
You would look great in a scarf.
It hides the turkey neck.
We live together,we like each
other,we're halfway there.
Sure,sure. Mailman
already thinks we're gay.
Yeah,he does.
At night,we could sit out on the
deckand grill up a couple steaks.
Steaks? Who are we kidding? Seared ahi.
Oh,better. Maybe some couscous?
- I love couscous!
- Yeah!
Then,after dinner,we could
go inside and watch the game.
Or if the game's a blowout,we
switch to Project Runway.
Yeah! Yeah,what do you think?
Mr. and Mr. Walden Schmidt.
So I would take your name?
Why wouldn't we take my name?
'Cause I'm the breadwinner.
So you think making a home isn't work?
I am sorry.We'll hyphenate.
- Schmidt-Harper.-
Harper-Schmidt.
Fine.
I'll order the towels.
So,listen,um,would we be
having sex like guys do?
I would.You'd be having
sex more like a woman does.
- Hmm.
- Problem?
No,I'm open to it. No pun intended.
But?
Look,I'm willing to
take one for the team;
it's just... if this doesn't work out,
I'd have to know I'm
gonna be provided for.
What is that supposed to mean?
It means I'm not signing a prenup.
Excuse me,is this seat taken?
No,help yourself.
Thanks.
Yo,forget what I said
about giving up women.
No,yeah,I was just goofin'.
I'm Walden.
So close.
I told you I had a big backyard.
You didn't tell me it was so... wet.
Yeah,I got to get my sprinklers checked.
This happens every day.
Are you okay?
Yeah,I think so.
No,I don't think so.
Um,are you as high as I am?
I'm pretty baked.
You're also pretty pretty.
Are you ready to get freaky?
I am way ahead of you.
You must think I'm awfully easy.
No,I think you're wonderfully easy.
Uh-oh,here we go again.
I didn't expect anything like this
to happenwhen I went to a bar alone
in a short skirt and no underwear.
Ah,geez.
What's the matter?
Nothing. I...I'm just
coming out of a bad breakup,
so I'm a little shaky.
That's okay.
I know how to make you forget her.
You still thinking
about your girlfriend?
No.It's my ex-wife this time.
Okay. Let's try again.
Mommy!
Mommy?
Okay... Daddy.
Can we just hold on for a second?
Am I doing something wrong?
No,no.I,um...I might
just be a little too high.
Okay,let's slow it down.
I got nowhere to be.
Great.
I could kiss you all night long.
I could have made him scream like that.
I'm really sorry.
Me,too.
I don't usually mistake
the women I'm sleeping with
for adult contemporary pop artists.
That's new.
I need air.
All right,no pot for a while.
Oh,bull dunny.
It wasn't the pot.
Would you please just
get out of my head?
Yelling's not gonna solve
your problems,Walden.
Oh,damn it.
Women leaving,that's your problem.
Not right now,it isn't!
It was my fault,really.
Oh,great.
I was the first to abandon him.
Oh,you didn't abandon
him; you had a career.
Tell him that.
Would,uh... just all of
you just leave me alone?!
Go away,I tell you! Go away!
No way I'm signing a prenup.
You know what? Just get out of my head!
All of you,just leave me alone!
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=-
-=http://ytet.org=-   proudly presents
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=-Sync:
YTET- ÑÅ±´
Two And a Half
Men  Season 10 Episode 1